NAGA AJAY K

+91 9113092795 · nagaajay9535@gmail.com · github.com/nagaajay4 Bengaluru,Karnataka

PASSIONATE FULL STACK DEVELOPER

A motivated and passionate full stack developer with several years of experience in developing and maintaining web applications and web apis using .NET, .NET core, React, MySQL and MongoDB. Created user-friendly and efficient web applications and delivered quality solutions as per the client requirements. I have started learning python and prompt engineering as AI is on boom.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Technology Solutions Programmer Analyst

August 2021- Present

I am responsible for developing and maintaining software applications. I have worked with the team of senior developers to create new features and fix bugs in existing applications. I have created, coded, and tested new features of a software.

Accomplishments:

- Developing and maintaining web and enterprise applications using various technologies, such as .NET, ASP.NET, React, MySQL, etc.
- Developing Web API applications with bearer authentication and following API Development Standards
- Applying advanced programming, matured coding skills and full stack abilities to create userfriendly and efficient products.
- · Collaborating and communicating effectively with cross-functional teams and stakeholders.
- Following software development methodologies, such as Agile, SCRUM.

Hermitcrabs Technologies

January 2021- April 2021

Website Design/Maintenance - Internship

I got familiar with the tech stack that the organization uses. I am exposed to Hubspot, CMS, and growth-driven design. Participated in design and development of Covid helper website for a hospital.

Accomplishments:

- Developing CMS(content management system) application for a hospital client.
- Identifying a problem and solving it.
- Collaborating and communicating effectively with client to understand the requirement.
- Doing A/B testing for the developed application for enriching the user experience.

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

.NET & .NET Core C# SQL

React Python MongoDB

Web API TypeScript JavaScript

STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

Problem-solving capability Analytical skills Team Work
Communication skills Open Source Detail Oriented
Writing skills Resourceful Inquisitiveness

EDUCATION

PES Unversity Computer Science & Engineering

July 2017 - August 2021

Successfully Completed computer science graduation from the college, acquired knowledge and practical experience in the foundations of Computer Science and engineering. Learned to be highly-motivated and results-driven, able to work and learn as individual and dedicated teams..

Accomplishments:

- · Participated in various college level and inter-college level competitions, hackathons
- Secured 3rd place in KALPANA inter-college 24 hours hackathon.
- · Volunteered for college fest and events.

PROJECTS

OPEN SOURCE

Contributing to open source projects

I have contributed to open-source projects and worked on various libraries and frameworks. Helped in setting up of open source projects, understanding the issues and asking for help when need for implementing better solution.

EMPLOYEE MANAGEMENT WEB APPLICATION .Net & React

Team size: 2

Implementing the requirements of a role-based application. There are mainly 2 roles, Admin and Employee. The main purpose of this application is to provide the ability to Search, Add, Edit and Delete the employee details as an admin and view the details as a employee. The technologies used are React JS based UI and .Net Core Web API based services along with MySQL database deployed to azure.

Twitter Application
.Net & React
Team size : 4

Tweet App is a SPA (Single Page App) for registered users to post new tweets, reply to tweets, like/unlike tweets. Guest users can see only see tweets but cannot interact with tweets. The core modules of tweet app are user registration and login, post tweet, view users/handles and their respective tweets, likes. The technology consists of React JS based UI, Redux to maintain application state and .Net Core Web API based services along with MongoDB database.

CERTIFICATIONS

30 DAYS OF GOOGLE CLOUD

Google program provides the opportunity to get started with cloud computing and get hands-on practice.

TRAVEL & HOSPITALITY- 101

The course is a practical and beginner-friendly introduction to travel and hospitality industry, its functioning and various software solutions used.

DATA ANALYSIS WITH PYTHON: ZERO TO PANDAS

The course is about data analysis covering the basics of Python, Numpy, Pandas, Data Visualization, and Exploratory Data Analysis.

Learn Python Programming: Python 3

In this course I am able to create Python programs with ease. I learnt python programming and various concepts used in it.